export const questions = [
  {
    question: "Which is NOT a route of drug administration?",
    options: ['Intravenous', 'Nasal', 'Digital', 'Oral'],
    answer: 2
  },
  {
    question: "Administration refers to:",
    options: ['Drug metabolism', 'How drug reaches circulation', 'Drug excretion', 'Drug storage'],
    answer: 1
  },
  {
    question: "Which organ is important in drug elimination?",
    options: ['Kidney', 'Skin', 'Eye', 'Ear'],
    answer: 0
  },
  {
    question: "Bupivacaine belongs to:",
    options: ['Esters', 'Amides', 'Opioids', 'Barbiturates'],
    answer: 1
  },
  {
    question: "Procaine is classified as:",
    options: ['Amide', 'Ester', 'Opioid', 'Benzodiazepine'],
    answer: 1
  },
  {
    question: "Peripheral regional anesthesia targets:",
    options: ['Local nerves', 'Spinal cord', 'Brain stem', 'Lungs'],
    answer: 0
  },
  {
    question: "General anesthesia can be given by:",
    options: ['Inhalation only', 'IV only', 'Both IV and inhalation', 'Topical only'],
    answer: 2
  },
  {
    question: "Ketamine IV is used for:",
    options: ['Analgesia', 'Antibiotic effect', 'Blood pressure reduction', 'Antacid'],
    answer: 0
  },
  {
    question: "Barbiturates are mainly for:",
    options: ['Muscle relaxation', 'Unconsciousness', 'Analgesia', 'Antibiotic use'],
    answer: 1
  },
  {
    question: "Succinylcholine causes:",
    options: ['Sedation', 'Analgesia', 'Muscle relaxation', 'Vomiting'],
    answer: 2
  },
  {
    question: "Halothane is given by:",
    options: ['IV', 'Oral', 'Inhalation', 'IM'],
    answer: 2
  },
  {
    question: "Preoperative assessment includes lab:",
    options: ['Astrology', 'Investigations', 'Horoscope', 'Dream analysis'],
    answer: 1
  },
  {
    question: "Monitoring includes PR which means:",
    options: ['Pulse rate', 'Pain ratio', 'Patient record', 'Pressure ratio'],
    answer: 0
  },
  {
    question: "Respiratory rate is abbreviated as:",
    options: ['BP', 'RR', 'HR', 'XR'],
    answer: 1
  },
  {
    question: "Weight is important in anesthesia because it affects:",
    options: ['Dose calculation', 'Hair growth', 'Eye color', 'Voice'],
    answer: 0
  },
];